In terms of this particular session, but just to help you all understand, as far as my understanding goes, I think we will take roughly one hour 45 minutes to two hours for this particular session.
And not sure if you have accounted so much time, if it is less or more, but I just wanted to make sure that I convey this at the start of the session.
What am I going to cover today and why are we going to talk for one hour for three minutes or one hour 45 minutes roughly.
So there are three major things that I intend to cover with you today in this particular session.
The first is to help you all understand what data points do you really look at while there are, let's say, 1000 or equity schemes available in the market.
How do you lay down the first filter in making sure that out of these 1000 art schemes, which are those 100 schemes that I really want to look into.
So the first layer or the first point of interaction that we are going to have is how do we break down the past data in terms of performance to be able to narrow down from 1000 schemes to 100 schemes that we really want to work with.
To work around in terms of a selection process.
So in the first part of our presentation, we are going to look at the past performance of the fund and I'm going to help you all understand some key metrics to look at while you look at the past performance of the fund.
For you to be in a position to understand that out of these 100 schemes 900 schemes don't fit into my my research basket and I'm only going to look at these 100 schemes which qualify basis my parameters.
Once we understood which are which are these 100 schemes that we really want to focus on to given our data points basis which we categorized them then we will split those 100 schemes into two different parameters.
First parameter I'm going to help you all understand is a simple parameter that probably all 300 of you are on the call will be able to do without without any technical know how is where I'm going to help you all understand how to look at the current portfolio of the fund to be in a position to understand whether this current portfolio will perform in the near future or will not perform in the near future.
And then the third data point that I'm going to help you all understand is slightly technical is where we will do a deep dive in the portfolio for you all to understand whether this portfolio is meant for me to invest today or it is not going to perform for me in the future.
Very quickly there are three things that we are going to learn first we are going to learn or how can we really look at the past performance of the scheme on some criteria that I will list down for you all and filter out schemes that you don't want to work on and design some 1500 schemes that will qualify the this filtration process that these are the schemes that I really want to do more research on.
And once we've decided those 1500 schemes that we want to do research on we will split our 50 schemes into two where one we will try and understand some basic data points to look at which may be a lot more.
And you will understand whether you should invest in this scheme or not in the second is a detailed understanding of the portfolio where you will be in a position to categorically identify whether should I invest in this portfolio or not but I'm going to take one hour 45 minutes roughly for me to be able to do this.
So, if I'm able to add value to you all and you think you have time please stay by till the end I guarantee you will learn definitely a couple of things that you were not looking at while looking at equity schemes in the past very quickly at any point in time you all have any questions to ask me.
Do you all have any questions to ask me while I talk to you all about this particular subject please don't wait for a Q and a session at the end right if you all have a question just use the chat box ask your question then and there and I'll be more than happy to take up all of those questions in the meanwhile that I'm having that conversation with.
So, don't wait till the end keep throwing your questions relevant to the topic that I'm discussing using the chat box on that note I'm going to start so it's 410 and I would try my level best to complete this by 6pm with your permission let me start so now there are 1000 let's say equity schemes available in the market now it is practically impossible for all of us to look at 1000 schemes.
And be in a position to figure out that out of these 1000 schemes which are those fight schemes that we want to invest in so the first thing that we really have to do is narrow down or reduce these 1000 schemes down to some 20 50 odd schemes on which you can actually do a deep dive and do research now how do you reduce these 1000 schemes into 20 or 50 schemes on which you will do further research is you look at their past performance.
Now I'm sure a lot of y'all probably look at various other matrix to identify whether the past performance has been good or past performance has been bad but I personally follow my own process of filtering from these 1000 schemes coming down to these 20 50 schemes using my own filtration process of of how do I figure out if the fund has had good or better.
So what I'm going to do is now help you understand our first our five step process that we personally look at to filter out to filter out and decide which are these 20 schemes of 50 schemes that we really need to put in a lot of effort on depending on the past data and these are the five data points that I personally look at I personally look at to filter.
Now all I'm going to do is first I'm going to run y'all through these five filtration process or these five step process that I follow to filter and then I will see if there are questions relating to the topic I'll take them out.
So let me start first okay now I've generally seen a lot of us a lot of us make this a prominent mistake which is we look at the past returns of the fund right we we look at the fund's written over one year three year five year seven year because this is this is what value research shows us 10 year.
10 year and probably we look at it since inception and we see whether the fund has been able to beat beat the benchmark or the fund has been able to beat the beat the category like value research shows and if the fund has done well over one year three or five year seven year 10 year and since inception period versus the benchmark or the category.
We say that the fund is good and we end up recommending that that fund to our investors now this is the first mistake I really want to identify all of you all here on the call never do this right and there are hundred reasons why I can give you that this will not give you the right data point to look at the funds in terms of their past performance right do not look at this data point and select your funds.
So why point number one why this will not work let's try and understand so I tweeted some days back and I'm going to talk about that very important data point of why doing this analysis does not work but does not give you the right picture of why the fund has been a good or a bad performer in the past look what happens is imagine that the last one year of the fund last one year of the fund the fund gave 50% returns.
So we're saying that just the last one year somebody saying that the volume is not good can you all just confirm it the volume is okay yes no.
Yeah volume is fine I've got a lot of pictures if you can maybe speak a bit in Hindi also.
Sorry what do you want me to do?
I think as you can mix the Hindi also.
Sure sure I'll use Hindi.
Okay thank you so much.
Thank you so much.
So I believe that the last one year of the fund, the last one year of the fund was 50% return.
Now like the last one year of the fund, the last one year of the fund was 50% return.
This is extremely important for you to understand very important for you to understand this is how it will not give you the right picture.
Because if you're looking at 5 years data point, this one year will be included in this five year.
If you're looking at this seven year, this year is extended.
If you're looking at 10 year returns, this year is extended.
If you're looking at since inception, this year is extended.
What I'm trying to tell you is, if the last one year performance of the fund is good,
automatically the three or five year, seven year, ten year in since inception will start
looking better.
So, if the return of the last one year is good, then it will take up to three years, five
years, seven years, ten years in since inception or fund consistently since inception
is good.
No.
So, only reason why the fund is showing you better returns on three or five year, seven
year, ten year and since inception is because your last one year return has been significant
and well demonstrated.
Similarly, if your last one year return is minus 50%, then suddenly you will realize
that three years, five year, seven year, ten year and since inception returns also don't
show you a good picture.
So, while you do this analysis of looking at one year, three or five year, seven year,
ten year and since inception returns and comparing it with benchmark and category, all you are
doing is giving importance to the fund's near-term performance.
So, near-term, if the fund is good, then automatically your one year, three years, five
years, seven years, seven years, seven years, ten years.
And if your fund has not done well in the last one year, automatically your three or five
years, seven year, ten years since inception returns will start looking bad.
So, the first point that I really want to help you understand is do not look at one year,
three or five year, seven year, ten year return compared with benchmark and category
average.
and start assuming that the fund has been performing well for the last 10 years,
or the fund has been performing well for the last 10 years,
it has been consistently performing well for the last 10 years,
this is one common mistake that I have seen or how many people look at it.
So, the first point that I really want you all to understand,
if you all really want to look at the past performances,
you have to look at something called as rolling returns.
Now, I am sure a lot of you all year on the call, probably,
what are the rolling returns and how are the rolling returns working?
But in the larger interest of all my audience,
let me try and explain to you the rolling returns.
Let's say, for example, if I am talking about the last 10-year investment
history of a particular fund.
Manlija Ambatkar Reff first, Jan 2011,
Laker 31st December, but don't mind me writing it,
31st December, 2020. Guys, I am trying my level best to use Hindi English mix.
I understand that there are my friends here from the south as well who can't
understand Hindi, but there are also friends who want
who don't understand English. I am trying my level best to give my Hindi English
donobakaru. Please, you know, try and adjust to this situation
because we have friends from both the sides, okay? So, we are saying,
we are saying, 1st Jan 2011, say, Laker, we are talking about the fund
which has history for 10 years up to 31st December, 2020.
Right? Now, what is rolling return? So, now try and understand,
if we are talking about this ABC fund from 1st Jan 2011 to 31st December, 2020.
Now, I want to know how consistent the fund has been.
So, I want to know that, had I invested in this fund,
had I invested in this fund, whenever,
when ever between the 1st Jan 2011 to the 31st of December, 2020,
had I invested whenever and held on to the fund for three years.
What have, what would have been my return? Now, pay attention, how is this very
different from what value research or the fund fact shield shows?
Fund fact shield, what is that? That if you are on the 31st of December, 2020,
fund fact shield says that had you invested on the 31st of December,
2017 and held on to three years, what would have been your return?
This is what the fund fact shield and the value research shows for three years return.
But, my point is, my point is that had I invested from the 1st of Jan 2011
till the 31st of December, 2020, between these 10 years at any point in time,
at any point in time, had I invested for three years, what could have been my return?
That is what value research or the fund fact shield does not show,
right? Because value research and the fund fact shield is showing only the last three years,
2017, 2020. Now, is exactly where rolling returns comes into picture.
So, how does rolling return really work? So, pay attention, how does rolling return work?
So, now, what rolling return does is assumes that you would have invested on the 1st of Jan,
2011 and held for three years, up to 1st of Jan, 2014.
So, how much return will you get? Let's say 12%. Then, it will assume that,
had you invested on the 2nd of Jan 2011 and held on for three years, 2nd of Jan,
2014, how much return would you have made? Let's say 11%. He'll keep assuming that you invested on
every day, every day for the last 10 years and held for three years. So, it would assume that you
invested on the 8th of October, right, 2011 and held till 8th of October, and held till 8th of October,
2014, right, what return would you have generated? 2014, what return would you have generated? Let's say
your return would have been minus 5%. He'll keep assuming you investing every day. Then he'll assume
that, let's say you invested on the 21st of July, 2012, stayed invested till 21st of July, 2015,
what could have been your return? So, let's say your return would have been 10%.
So, he'll assume that you invested on the 1st of July, the last date that it will assume will be the 31st
of December, 2017 that you stayed invested on the 1st of December, 2020. Look,
what 31st December, 2017, ke baadvala date nahile sakavai, because if it takes 1st of December,
2018, it does not have a 3-year period, because 1st of Jan, 2018, 3-year period will be 1st of
Jan, 2021, but we are only talking up to 31st of December. So, the last date it will assume that you
invested was 31st of December, 2017 and he'll assume that you invested up to 31st December, 2020,
and let's say your return would have been, let's say 6%. Now, understand what is happening. It is
assuming that you are investing on every day for the last 10 years and holding on for 3 years. You
invested on the 1st of Jan, held for 3 years, 2nd of Jan, held for 3 years, 3rd of Jan, held for 3 years,
4th of Jan, held for 3 years, so on and so forth, 8th of October, held for 3 years, you moved to the next year,
21st of July, you held for 3 years, moved to another year, let's say 8th of October, 2013, held
till 2016, then he'll assume that you invested on the 8th of October, 2014, and held till 2017.
So, he'll assume that in the last 10 years, 10 years, had you invested every day,
had you invested every day and held on to 3 years, right, what could have been your return.
Now, assume this, assume this. In one year, there are 240 days where you can invest,
removing Saturday and Sunday, and removing bank holidays. So, in one year, you could have invested
for 240 days, correct. Now, so, you could have invested 240 days in 2011, you could have
invested 240 days in 2012, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17. Look, your last date is 31st December, 2017,
which means out of 10 years, you could have invested in 7 years every day,
this means, you could have got 200 days where you could have invested. So, I'm repeating again,
last 10 years, last 10 years, right, if you invest any day, and had you held on for 3 years,
you could have had 1500 days, 1500 days that you could have invested and held on for 3 years,
and which means, you could have had 1500 returns, you could have had 1500 returns. Now,
what does rolling return do? Simple, rolling return adds all of these daily returns that you invested
on the 1st of Jan, stayed invested for 3 years, you could have got 12%, then 11%. So, 12 plus 11,
23, minus 5, 18, plus 10, 28, plus 6, 34. So, if you got 1500 returns, 1500 returns,
he'll add all of those 1500 returns. Let's say, the total of all of those 1500 returns,
turned out to be 15,000%, 15,000% right? Now, 15,000% is your return adding these 1500 daily returns,
correct? Divide it by 1500 observations. So, your total return is 15,000%,
15,000% is your daily return is 10%. Now, try and understand what I'm trying to say,
try and understand what I'm trying to say. This entire analysis shows you, entire analysis shows you
that between 1st of Jan, 2011 and 31st of December, 2020, if you invested at any point in time,
Kabibi invest, Kabibi, and had you held on for 3 years, if you hold that investment for 3 years,
so, every return, Kabibi, 10% is your return. Repeat what I said. Fact sheet, what does it say?
Fact sheet says that, Fact sheet says that today is the 31st of December, 2020. Now, if today you want
to look at, you want to look at 3 years return of the fund, the fact sheet will show you return
of investment done on 31st of December, 2017, up to December, 2020. But it is not necessary that
you invested on the 31st of December and held on till 31st of December, 2020, right? You could
have invested at any point in time in held on for 3 years, that is the problem rolling return
solves for you, right? Now, you are saying, I want to know that in the last 10 years, last 10 years,
last 10 years, had I invested at any point in time, had I invested at any point in time and stayed
invested and stayed invested for 3 years, what could have been my return? Your return would be 10%
that is what rolling return helps you understand. So, unlike Fact sheet, you have a point
31st of December, 2017, from the 2nd point, 31st of December, 2020, the return tells you that had you
invested at any point in time between 1st of January, 2011 to 31st of December, 2020 and held on for
3 years, you could have got 10% return and this is what shows you the consistency of the fund, right?
I could have invested here and held on for 3 years, I could have invested here and held on for 3 years,
I could have invested here and held on for 3 years, I could have invested at any point in time in the
last 10 years and invested for 3 years, how much average return I could have bought? This is what you
look at to understand if the fund is consistent or not. Now, the point is, somebody is asking me
and very rightly so, and very rightly so, okay, where do I get this data? So, let me try and help you
understand, you go on to this website called advisorcoach.com, so go on to this website called
advisorcoach.com. Look guys, I'm going to talk about a lot of websites today in this particular
session, I've got nothing to do with any of these websites that I talked to you of just a disclaimer,
so you go to, you go to advisorcoach.com, you go to MF research and you go to rolling returns
versus benchmark, I will write it down here for everybody, so you go to advisorcoach.com,
you go to MF research and you go to rolling returns, rolling returns versus category. Now,
what do you do? Look, I don't want to talk good or bad about any fund, but I'm going to take examples
of two funds just to make sure that you all are understanding what I'm trying to say, okay,
please do not, please do not assume this to be in any form a recommendation or not a recommendation
for a particular fund, I'm only using it for education purpose. Now, let's say for example,
okay, let's look at this fund which advisorcoach shows you initially, okay, let's say let's say
I see, I see a prudential blue chip, right? Now, I'm going to take my start date back to 2011,
so I will say, I will say 27th, so look, I selected 27th of October, 27th of October, 2010,
so it gives me 10 years of data that I'm talking about, and I will select a three year rolling period,
you can select two year, you can select one year, you can select one month, I do three years,
I will explain to you later why I take three years, and why I feel three years is a better judgment
to look at, so I took my starting date 10 years back and I looked at the rolling period for three years,
I click submit, so when I click submit, I get this data point, right? Do you see this average?
Do you see this average? So, I'm going to write it here, so let's say I see, I see, I see, I see, I
blue chip has been consistently delivering 13.81% return on a rolling basis, versus category,
category is 12.97, which means this is okay for me, look, this 10 year rolling, the three year
rolling over 10 year that I'm talking to you of has to beat the category, is it beating the category,
the answer is yes, so I will be okay to move to the second step, but I'm going to take one more
fund so that you and I both can understand a comparative analysis, let's say we look at, again please
don't misunderstand me on any fund, I'm just randomly taking any fund that comes to my head,
let's say Nippon India, Nippon India, large cap, okay, so that it's an Apple to Apple comparison,
so look, Nippon India large cap, again that starting date is the same, rolling return three
year is the same, I will click submit, okay, now what has been the average return, 14.90,
right, this is Nippon India, Nippon India blue, sorry, Nippon India large cap,
so now understand step one, step one is don't look at the last, don't look at the last three or
five years, seven year, 10 year data point, guys I will tell you why I'm taking three years and not
five years just give me some time, right, so do not look at what value research shows you three
and five years, seven year, 10 year data point, it is useless, you have to look at the rolling
returns, right, like I showed you and that rolling return, that rolling return has to beat,
has to beat your category average or your benchmark, right, so step one, both of these funds look
okay to me, step one, but this is not the final verdict, step one, both of these funds look okay to
me because on a rolling return basis, rolling return basis, they've been able to beat their benchmark
and the returns are pretty decent at 13.81 and 14.90, right, but this does not solve my purpose,
this is just the step one, step one, average three or rolling over 10 years, that I've done and
I've identified that both of these funds look okay to me, step two, I will now look at something called
as sortino ratio of the fund, right, now before I explain to you what that means,
how and where do you get the data from, let me try and explain to you what that what that actually
means, okay, okay, okay, so now let's time look at, look at sortino ratio first to try and understand
what that means, what is sortino ratio before we move to that, so what is sortino ratio, let's say
there are two funds, fund A and fund B, okay, fund A, fund A as generated, let's say 12% returns
and fund B as generated, let's say 15% returns, now suppose if I have to ask you which amongst both
of these funds is a good fund, what would your answer be, what would your answer be, is fund A good or
fund B good, okay, perfect, so we have a lot of people saying fund B but there are a couple of people
who are saying as if now or the data is not correct or the complete data is not given absolutely,
now look at a situation like this, let's say you come across somebody like me, right,
who let's say hypothetically, hypothetically let's say understands a little about investing,
now I'm going to argue with you that look risk free rate in the market is 7%, risk free rate in the
market is 7%, so if I'm investing in fund A, fund A is actually not generating 12% return for me,
fund A is only generating 5% returns for me, why, because I'm arguing and telling you that if I
invest in a fixed deposit today also I'm getting 7%, risk free without taking any risk, so if I'm
investing in your fund which gives me 12%, your fund has actually generated only 5% returns for
correct, right, now my question to you is if your fund has generated only 5% return for me,
if your fund has generated only 5% returns for me, how much downside risk has your fund taken,
right, how much downside risk has your fund taken to generate this return for me, when I say
downside risk, right, I am talking about standard deviation, downside standard deviation, look this is
a two hour session and I have a lot of things to cover, so I'm not going to go very deep in explaining
to you all how to calculate downside standard deviation, right, but what you have to understand is,
what you have to understand is that if I'm investing in this particular fund, I'm investing in
this particular fund, there is definitely going to be a risk that if the market falls, this fund is
also going to fall, now when the fund falls, we call it the downside standard deviation risk,
so now I'm asking a question to you that if your fund is generating 5% returns for that 5%
how much downside standard deviation risk is the fund taking, now you don't have to bother at
this funding time how to calculate this data because this data is calculated and given to you,
let's say the downside standard deviation risk of fund A is, let's say, let's say 20,
hypothetical, okay, let's say 10, it will be easier for me to calculate it, let's say 10, then I am
saying that for you to get me 5% returns, you to 10 units of downside risk, so what is the return
per unit of downside risk have you generated for me, so pay attention to what I'm trying to say,
you're saying the fund might have generated 12% returns, the fund might have generated 12% returns,
but I'm arguing that without taking any risk, I could have got 7% returns from the market,
so your fund has not generated 12%, your fund has only generated 5% returns for me,
but to generate this 5% return, you took risk, no, how much risk, so I'm saying to generate
this 5% return, let's say the downside risk you took was 10, so now I'm arguing to generate 5% returns,
you took 10 units of risk, which means per unit of risk you generated 0.5% returns,
so this 0.5% is called the sortino ratio, okay, it helps you understand
that for every unit of downside risk, every unit of downside risk, how much return is your fund
generating, again you don't have to calculate this, this is already calculated and given to you,
I will show you where, just give me some time, similarly, let me talk about fund B with your,
okay, now I'm saying that fund B generated 15% returns, but the downside risk that fund B
took was let's say 20 units, okay, now we are saying fund B generated 15% returns,
but I could have got 7% returns without taking any risk, right, so how much return has the fund
actually generated for me, the fund has generated 8% returns for me, now if the fund has generated
8% returns for me, how much downside risk did the fund take, right, so we are saying that the
fund took 20 units of downside risk, which means we are saying for every unit of downside risk,
fund B has generated 0.4% returns, sortino ratio, okay, now try and understand what I'm saying,
fund, sorry, this is fund B, my bad, my bad, fund B is taking one unit of risk and generating 0.4%
returns, fund A is generating taking one unit of risk and generating 0.5 returns, which means websites
will show you that sortino ratio of fund A is 0.5 and it will show you sortino ratio,
sortino ratio of fund B, sorry, sortino ratio of fund B is 0.4, now I showed you the calculation,
but in the real world you don't have to calculate, it is already calculated and shown you,
but when it shows you sortino as 0.5, it means that the fund has generated 0.5% return
for unit of downside risk, and fund B has generated 0.4% returns per unit of downside risk,
now tell me, while you look at risk also, that the funds took how much risk versus that what
return was generated, do you think fund A is a better bet or fund B is a better bet,
what do you think, fund A is a better bet or fund B is a better bet, absolutely, so guys,
you should not get carried away, you should not get carried away, while you look at fund B generating 15%
return is because there is a sound possibility to generate 15% return, the fund would have taken very
high risk, whereas fund A generated 12% return by taking low risk, so while you consider risk taken
to generate returns, you will say fund B is a better, a fund A is a better bet, look at it this way,
fund A, fund B both are multi-cap funds, but fund B invested most of its money in
media cap and small cap and hence generated 15%, whereas fund A invested all the money in large
cap and generated 12%, now both the multi-cap funds are not the same, right, though the category looks
the same, but the risk both the funds have taken a very different, so when I compare versus the risk
taken the return generated, I understand that fund A is a better bet because fund A has generated
higher, so TNO versus fund B, now where do you get this data, very simple, where do you get that
get this data, is as simple as you don't have to calculate any of these things, okay, go to value
research, go to value research, okay, now our first fund was on the basis of which we started
understanding was ICICF blue chip, now always ignore these star ratings and I'll show you why,
keep going down, here you get the SOTNO ratio, so SOTNO ratio of ICICF blue chip is minus 0.01,
versus what is the index SOTNO ratio, 0.12, so it's the reject, so pay attention, we said fund ICICF
blue chip and we said another fund that we were discussing was NIPON large cap, now we said while we
looked at the rolling returns, both funds looked good, this showed some 13%, they showed some 14 and a half
percent, now I don't remember the exact number, but we said both of them beat the category, so on this
data both of the, both funds were good to go ahead, but then when we looked at SOTNO, now look at SOTNO,
so TNO, ICICF blue chip is minus 0.01, is it able to beat the benchmark, no, so minus 0.01,
it's not able to beat the benchmark, this is, this fund is a reject, right now here, I will not even
go to step 3, this fund becomes a reject for me, let's look at NIPON, so I look at let's say NIPON
in the large cap, okay, now I keep going down, now look the SOTNO here shows minus 0.12,
am I beating the category, absolutely not, absolutely not, so in both of these cases, though they are
average rolling returns in terms of consistency of the fund has been good over the last 10 years,
but both of these funds have taken higher risk and they've not been able to justify that risk
taken, versus the return generated, and hence on the SOTNO ratio, they've not been able to beat
their category average, or sorry, their benchmark, and hence I would not go ahead with either ICICF
chip nor will I go ahead with NIPON large cap, now these are only two steps so far, let's hypothertically as
you, hypothertically that this also turns out to be in favor of both the funds, then I will look at my
third data point, which is look at the alpha of the fund, now before I move ahead, I just want to
quickly get a yes or a no, guys just give me a yes or a no, if you all have understood both of these
things so far or whatever I've explained to you, okay, let's move to the third point,
Krishna, so SOTNO ratio is only for the last three years, right, which is exactly why thank you for
asking this question, now look what is happening is, what is happening is that why we looked at the
rolling returns, while we looked at the rolling returns up to the 31st of December 2020, the last
data point was 31st of December 2017, so it said that up to 31st of December, you invested at any
point in time, any point in time in held for three years, held for three years, right, it would have
shown you the rolling returns, but one disadvantage of rolling returns is it ignores the recent
performance, it ignores the recent performance and that recent performance solution is taken care
by SOTNO, so while we discuss SOTNO it talks about the last three years only, so it takes the last three
years into consideration and hence the slight disadvantage that we had in rolling is taken care in
SOTNO ratio bit because it talks about these three years that we missed out on. Krishna, have I answered
your question? Have you understood? Okay, perfect, perfect, perfect guys, whatever questions you'll have,
if I missed out on any of these questions, I will definitely take these questions up again at the end
if time permits, if time permits and y'all are able to bear with me up to up to 6 o'clock, so Sujata
generally the SOTNO ratio that value research shows is for the last three years, yes, right, okay,
now let's say hypothertic in, so we are saying we will select the fund which has higher rolling,
we will select the fund which has higher SOTNO because higher SOTNO means that let's say
higher SOTNO means that for every unit of risk taken, your fund is generating higher return,
higher unit of risk, your fund is generating higher return, so amongst these I will take this,
so you will generally take a fund which has a higher sharp risk, higher SOTNO ratio,
I also helped explain to you how SOTNO takes care of this small disadvantage that rolling brings on
now let's say for example, a fund is able to show us good result on SOTNO, sorry, on rolling returns,
a fund is able to show us good returns on SOTNO, then the third step we will look at is alpha,
right, now before I move ahead what is alpha, what is alpha, so in very simple terms, alpha is not,
I see a lot of people, I see a lot of people assume alpha to be fund returns,
so a lot of people tell me alpha is 3%, which means if benchmark gave 12%, and fund gave 15%,
so alpha is 3, no, this is actually called active returns in the real world,
now what is alpha, try and understand, let's say you have 100 rupees,
let's say you have 100 rupees, the first option you have to deploy this 100 rupees,
the first option you have to deploy this 100 rupees is investing, let's say fixed deposit which
pays you 7%, we will call this as risk free returns, okay, so you are saying without taking any risk,
is there some return that I can generate, yes, investing FD, you will get 7%, but
then we also argue with our self that if we invest in FD, we will not be able to beat inflation,
so why not invest in markets, but if I invest in markets, then I want higher returns,
right, then I want higher returns, I will not be satisfied with 7% returns on the F,
on that the FD gave, I want 5% returns more because of the risk that I am taking by investing in
the market, so if I invest in FD, I get 7%, which is risk free, but if I'm investing in market,
I am not happy with risk free, I want more returns because I am taking risk, correct,
now the third case is, what if, sorry, the third case is, what if the client is investing in an
MF, so if the client is investing in an MF, then the returns that the client will expect will be
dependent on the return that the risk that the MF is taking, I repeat, if the client is investing
in FD, 7%, risk free, client is investing in market ETF, Lelia, index fund Lelia, right, then the
client is expecting returns equivalent to the market, 7% of risk fee plus 5% for the risk that I am
taking by investing in the market, but if the client is investing, if the client is investing in an MF,
client is investing in an MF, client is expecting better risk adjusted returns,
depending on the risk that the fund is taking, now let's say the fund is taking one beta risk,
you would have, all of you are on the call I am sure I have ordered this concept called beta,
right, so let's say the client, if the fund is taking one beta risk, then what is the return that
the client is expecting, so the client is saying, if I invest in FD, I get 7% plus, if you are going to put my
money, my money in the market, I am expecting 5% for the risk that I am taking, if you are taking
market risk, look, any index risk is always one, so sensex or nifty always has a beta of one,
so I am saying if the mutual fund is taking risk similar to the index, then my return expectation from
the fund is similar to that of the index 12, but if my fund is taking two times risk of the index,
so index risk is one and my funds risk is two, right, then the return I am expecting from the fund is
twice, twice that of the risk I am expecting, so pay attention of what I am trying to tell you,
very important and I want you to understand, let's say there are two funds, fund A,
is taking similar risk to that of the index, so what is the return expectation you will have
from the fund similar to that of the market, but if there is another fund which is taking twice
the risk of the index, is it logical that you will expect the fund to give returns equivalent to index,
of course not, if you are taking twice the return or twice the risk then the index, then your
minimum return expectation has to be higher than the index, right, how do you calculate that like
this, so if your fund is taking two beta risk, what is the return expectation that you have from the fund,
17, you don't have return expectation equivalent to the market because your fund is taking higher risk than
the market, let's say your fund is taking lower risk than the market, again then your return expectation
is not equivalent to the market, but lower than market, how much, I am saying 7% I should get because that
is something everybody is getting investing in FB also, but the risk that is taken is half that of index,
so I should get returns half that of index, so my return expectation here now will be 9.5%.
Look, this is a misconception that all of us have that our fund should be the index, no,
if our fund is taking risk equivalent to the index, then our fund should give equivalent
returns to the index, but if our fund is taking higher risk than the index, then our expectation is
not return by the index, our expectation is much higher than the return of the index, if our fund is
taking lower returns, a lower risk than the index, then we don't expect the fund to beat the index,
we expect the fund to beat 9.5 percent. Now, if your fund beats these returns that I'm talking
to you off, then you generate alpha. Let's say now if your fund's return is 15, your alpha is
3. Let's say if your fund's return is 15, your alpha is not free because your index has given 12
percent return, your alpha is minus 2. Because your minimum expected return was 17. Let's say now
your fund generates 15, your alpha is 5.5. So pay attention, alpha does not mean fund returns
minus benchmark. No, alpha means that depending on the risk, what is the return you are expected
to generate? If you beat that return, you generate alpha. Depending on the risk, your expectation
of minimum return is going to be higher. Are you beating that? No, you might have beaten 12 percent
of index return, but your expectation was 17. Have you beaten that 15? No, so your alpha will be
minus 2. Your index might have generated 12, but because you took lower risk, your return expectation
is lower, 9.5. Are you beating that? Yes, you are beating that and hence your alpha is 5.5. So
please understand, alpha is not fund return, alpha is not fund return minus index. This is actually
called active returns. Alpha means, alpha means funds return minus minimum return, minimum return,
minimum return, minimum return that the fund should have given you depending on the risk of the fund.
That is alpha. Okay, now a good thing, you don't have to calculate any of these things that I spoke
to you of. All you have to do is read the data, read the data, right? Now let me show you the same data.
So we go to the same website, value research, I will search on ICIC, I view shape, I will click
okay. Sorry, my internet is slightly slower. Okay, when we go down, so here you will see alpha,
now see alpha minus 2.28. Minus 2.28 alpha means minus 2.28 alpha means 2.28 alpha means 2.8 alpha
that ICIC, ICIC, I view shape fund was supposed to generate 10 percent depending on the risk it took.
Jitna risk, ICIC, I fund, I will generate that ICIC, I will generate 10 percent. But if that fund
is minus 2.28, that means fund is ideally, fund is ideally roughly 7.72 percent return is generated.
So whenever you see alpha minus, whenever you see alpha minus, you have to assume that fund
has generated less than minimum expected return. That is, Jitna risk, in front of it, Jitna return
generated was not generated that much return generated. Now look, alpha, alpha of ICIC, I see a
blue chip is minus 2.28. Again, it's a reject, right? Similarly, let's say Nippon, India,
large gap, only if the alpha is positive, you will go ahead with that particular fund. Reject,
minus 5 percent, this is called fund, Jitna return was supposed to generate 5 percent return
come dear, it's a reject. So pay attention, I will repeat, what was our step one?
We said ruling returns, higher the better, we said step two, only if this qualifies,
you go to step two, you say, so TNO ratio, okay, higher the better, in both cases, they have to
beat the benchmark, they have to beat the benchmark, step three, alpha, okay, positive should be
there, positive should be there. If this qualifies, then go to step two, go to step two, go to step two,
qualify, go to step three, go anywhere, qualify, you have a fund there, reject it. Step four or step five
interesting here, this is called up capture or down capture ratio, okay, up capture or down capture ratio
what happens, okay, up capture or down capture ratio, what happens, so first point number one,
I am sure all of y'all will agree, you all will agree with me that you have to invest in such a fund,
how to invest in such a fund, in which when the market goes up, your fund goes up more than the market,
and when the market goes down, your fund from the market goes up less, I will repeat,
you want to invest in a fund which when the market goes up, your fund goes up more than the market,
okay, and when the market goes down, your fund should fall less than the market,
correct, you want to invest in that fund, right, that is given by up capture and down capture ratio,
now what happens, be attention, what is up capture ratio, so if I look at up capture ratio for five years
of particular fund, of a particular fund, how does this calculation happen, how does this calculation happen,
so first, when you divide it, it is a ratio, it is a number, let's say 110 or 90, okay,
now what you have to understand is, the number of 100s or 100s or 100s or 100s,
it will mean that your fund does better than the market when the market goes up,
when the market goes up, the market goes up, your fund goes up, if the number of 100s or 100s or 100s is up,
if the number of 100s or 100s is down, it means that if the market goes up, your fund goes up,
but the market goes up less than the market, so you always want an up capture ratio,
you always want an up capture ratio of more than 100, up capture ratio of more than 100,
up capture ratio of more than 100, right, you will tell you that when the market went up
in the last five years, so your fund goes up more than the market, what is down capture ratio,
what is down capture ratio, the same thing is done, okay, in the last five years,
how many observations were there where the market went up, where the market went up, that's a minus 1,
minus 2, minus 0.5, minus 0.3, that's the same in the same day, the market went up,
now you can map it, now you will get two numbers,
back to 110, you can get a number of 90s, you can get a number of 90s,
90 means that when the market goes up, your fund goes up less,
and 110 means when the market goes up, your fund goes up more,
so you want a such a fund, which has down capture ratio less than 100,
so you will look for a fund which has more than 100 up capture ratio and has less than 100 down capture ratio,
okay, you have to give more importance to down capture ratio,
you have to give more importance to down capture ratio, because down capture ratio,
down capture ratio, you will tell you this, right, that when the market goes up,
your fund goes up as much as you want, now you will tell you the capture ratio,
when the market goes up, your fund goes up, I will repeat for people who lost it because of language,
up capture ratio, should be more than 100, should be 110, 105,
this shows you that when the markets were going up over the last five years,
whenever the market went up, let's say the market went up on the 20th of July,
how did your fund perform? If the number is more than 100,
it shows you that when the market went up, your fund went up more, this is a good sign,
you want a fund which has a down capture ratio,
which has a down capture ratio, sorry, which has a down capture ratio of less than 100,
right, let's say 95, what this shows you is, that when the market fell,
whenever in the last five years, on that particular day, your fund fell less than the market.
Now, if you will get confused in either of these things, you have to give importance to down capture ratio,
you always want to invest in a fund which falls less when the market is falling, data can be
so you go to morning star, so go to morning star,
the site is opening up, just give me a moment, okay, now just write the funds name here,
so let's say I see, I see a proof, view chip, right, I see, I see, I see,
view chip fund, why is it not showing, I see, I see, good,
good, good, good, good, good, good, good, good, good, good, so now be attention,
so we said, I see, I see, I see, I see, we said, step one, step one, we said rolling returns,
we said 13%, we said 14.5%, now this is a qualifier because both of them would beat the benchmark,
then we said step two, look at 14 ohm, we said 14 ohm was minus 0.0 to minus 0.12,
both of them were not able to beat the benchmark and it's both the funds were reject,
but let's say hypothetically, both of them, both the fund did beat this one, okay,
so we will go step three, then we saw alpha, this fund's alpha minus two points something,
something that is the minus fund, the back of both the funds rejected, this should be the plus,
then you will see, now capture, if we want to go through these three qualifiers,
then what will you see, now capture, down capture, now capture should be up to 100, down capture,
so can you show us, let's try and see, okay, so I have fund pay guy morning star pay,
now risk and return pay click on it, now click five years here, we will repeat this in the pond,
so that this will get revised, now click on five years, now look upside, up capture ratio
of the fund is 93, of the fund is 93, which means whenever the market went up by 100%,
let's say this fund went up only by 93%, again not a good sign, let's look at the down capture,
now the down capture is good 94, so if the market, if the market is 100%, so if the fund is 94%,
so this is a good sign, okay, now let's look at Nipon in the same case, Nipon, India,
large care growth, manpreet I think there is some problem at your end others are able to hear,
Amit you can take the Salkavi for a specific reason why I am taking it, I will explain it to you,
so you come on the fund, you click on risk and return, risk and rating, click on five years,
okay, 103, up capture 103, very good, okay, down capture, 121,
extremely aggressive fund, if the market is 100%, so it will be 111%, so it will be 111%, okay,
now look understand, what do you want to understand, if you want to beat the rolling bench mark,
then you will go to the next step, you will have to beat the 13th bench mark, then you will go to the next step,
you should be positive, then you will go to the next step, now capture, you should go up, down capture,
you should go down, only if a fund qualifies on all of these five matrix,
then you will be able to analyze the fund further, this is how you look at the past data,
now take care, in rolling returns we have taken 10 years of data, so TNO Alpha is naturally three years data,
now capture, down capture is five years, from this we have taken near term, medium term or long term,
in three time frames the fund is analyzed, which is why you use this framework to decide the past
basis for my research or not, so you will analyze the past data, understood, yes or no,
actually there are multiple funds who qualify on all five parameters, five parameters,
funds qualify, okay, so, so Suriyong is asking if both cases, I see I say Nippon,
we have seen negative, so TNO, can you please, yes, so we have seen negative, so TNO,
Suriyong in both the cases, what is the time frame used for alpha of capture and
so Ram, time frame used for alpha and so TNO like I explained to you is three years,
of capture, down capture is five years, Dr. Pankaj, I am not understanding what denominator are you
talking about, please if you could elaborate, can you get all of this information on one data,
one website, very difficult unless, if you are using a SMA or a software, or you will have to go to
Nippon, okay guys, I have a lot of questions coming up, but friends I have a lot of more things to
cover, I have a lot of data to cover, okay guys, anywhere, so Sanjee what you have to do is give
more importance to down capture ratio, your down capture ratio has to be, your down capture ratio is
more important than up capture ratio, on which you can get this on multiple websites, multiple
softwares, but why do you want to, why do you want to purchase money, when you are getting free,
so you will get rolling returns, you will get rolling returns on the advisor coach, you will get
SOTNO alpha, SOTNO alpha value research, you will get up capture down capture, you will get a
morning start, why do you want to buy money, when you can get it for free, guys, I know you all have a
lot of questions, but I have a lot of more things to cover, with your permission can I just move ahead
and take a lot of these questions at the end please, okay thank you so much guys, okay now let's say
for example, now let's say for example, you are in parameters, you are in parameters, let's say
BESIA 50 points shortlist, okay now you want to figure out that BESIA 50 points
which I have shortlisted, which ones do you want to buy today, because BES or 50 points,
let's say 50 points, they are all qualified on these five parameters that we spoke of, right,
so if all of these 50 points I have qualified on all the parameters, on all the parameters that we
spoke of, okay then in that case, then in that case in 50 points, say which one or two or five
points I select, is where now I am going to help you understand two two methods to looking to the
fund, which you can perform on the next fund, you will understand it, so till now we have seen that the fund
has performed in the past, now we will try to understand that the fund can perform on the next one,
how you identify it, okay so I am going to teach you two methods, one method is a simpler method that I
believe everybody here on the call will be able to do it, everybody here on the call will be able
to do it, and the second method that I will show you is slightly technical in nature, which all we
will have to pay attention to, for you to be able to do that in the real world, so let's then first
understand the first method, okay now before I take you to the first method, right, these are the
five data points that I spoke to you, before we understand the first method a little bit of your
basics are clear, so a little bit of a mid-set stock market, there are some mids in the stock market,
what is that mid, I think that higher P and higher P will be the stock expensive, and I think that
dividend yield stock is more attractive, I am sure a lot of you all here on the call also read a lot
of this commentary by a lot of people on social media, otherwise on the media and so on so forth,
okay if your PEPB is more expensive and the stock is expensive, and if your dividend yield is higher
than the stock is attractive, let me first before we move ahead break this myth forward, let me show you
some data points, okay let's go back to 2000 interesting, NTPC which is the biggest power producer,
okay, and torrent power which is not the biggest power producer, don't go and analyze it,
NTPC stock price XOTA is the 123, PE was 10.5, torrent power stock price was 162, PE was 21.4,
now if you go by the normal understanding that people give in the market or the normal
yarn that people give in the market, torrent power looks an expensive stock, correct,
similarly SBI, the biggest bank of India was trading as 0.85 price to book,
whereas HDFC was trading at 4.5 price to book, again,
if you go by the normal market, then the stock price to book 4.5 is SBI, so HDFC is expensive,
similarly, though I am going to explain to you what is PEPB dividend yield in some time again,
NMDC, right, the biggest iron or producer in our country was available for a dividend deal of 5%,
whereas JSW steel was available for 1.1, again, you will say, JS, JSW is not a good stock to buy,
so look, PE was higher torrent power, PE was higher HDFC,
or dividend yield was less in JSW, so you said torrent power HDFC, JSW are not good stocks,
these are good stocks and let's buy them, right, let's look fast forward to 2018, right,
NTPC stock price went up just 10% in three years, right, torrent power stock price went up 50%
in three years, SBI stock instead of going up went down, HDFC priced double in spite of you thinking
it was expensive, NMDC, the stock tank 20, 25%, JSW stock went up 300% in the same period,
okay, the point that I'm trying to make, the point that I'm trying to make to y'all,
okay, is, remember, higher PEPB, that means stock is expensive,
or higher dividend yield, that means stock is attractive, is wrong,
you have to understand when to invest in higher PEPB or higher dividend yield,
and you have to understand when to invest in lower PEPB and lower dividend yield stocks,
if you understand, then you understand, then you understand, right, when to invest in higher PEPB
portfolio and when not to invest in higher PEPB, just because the portfolio is higher PEPB does not
mean that the portfolio will not work, I hope that's clear to everybody around the corner,
now before I help you understand which portfolio will work when, before I help you understand
which portfolio will work when, let me first, for the benefit of everybody, you're in the audience,
explain to you what is PEP and what is PEP, I know a lot of y'all, you're on the call would know,
you know, a couple of people have PEPB, what is PEPB, they might already know, but I don't want to assume
that everybody here on my call knows about it and I'm going to spend some time explaining to you what it means,
there are times I don't know that this will explain it to you, but you have to understand,
if you want to understand the third method that I want to teach you, which is slightly technical,
so first of all, EPS is earning for share, okay, so now I'm saying, let's say for example,
so I go to this, so I went to this website called phenology.in,
and just writing it here, so you can use a lot of websites in your market,
where these websites are more comfortable, so I use this website,
so you go to this website called phenology.in,
then let's say you can also write a stock name, let's say reliance industries,
okay, reliance industries, okay, now you write your reliance industries, now you will understand it carefully,
you come here, you come here, you will go to PNL, you clicked on your reliance industries,
you clicked on your PNL, right, reliance industries, you clicked on PNL, now look,
now look at Net Profit, Net Profit, how much is the company's company,
30903 crore, Net Profit, Company's company's company's a 30903 crore,
this means the entire company put together for all shareholders, entire company put together for
all shareholders, company is on 30903 crore rupees, now my question is, per shareholder,
each share has a lot of income, per share, this 30903 crore is for the entire company,
for all 100% shareholders, how much is the company on per shareholder,
or per share, so earning per share means whatever the net profit is that you want for the entire
company divided by the number of shares, right, where do you get number of shares simple,
okay, do you see a number of shares, number of shares, right, 676.20 crores,
let me open an Excel to show you and we get simpler for you, now we are going to talk,
for the next half an hour we are going to talk some very interesting things, I just hope that you
not got very bored with me so far and we'll stay back for another hour, so let's say the shares,
the net profit of the company was let's say roughly 30903 crore, okay, this was the net profit,
okay, and then we are saying number of shares in the market, number of shares in the market are
676 crore and just rounding it off, per share profit you are earning skit now, I'm saying
31,000 crore for the entire company divided by 676 crore, we are saying per share earning
over 45.97, now again, now again you don't have to calculate all of these things, you don't have to
calculate all of these things, you already calculate Kiawa, you see this, now our answers are not matching
is because I have taken March 2020 data, we are in October 2020, right, so the answer will not exactly
match your, the point that I'm trying to tell you is that you need to calculate, you already
calculate Kiawa, you don't have to do anything, but I just wanted to explain to you how this number
is, okay, so we are saying that the company for the entire year is earning roughly 31,000 crore
for the entire year, but this is for 100% share holders, right, how much are you earning in front of one share,
so 39003 divided by number of shares, in front of one share, they earn roughly 45 crore, that's
what you call EPS, so earning, earning and sharing is 45 crore, that is if you have a reliance
industry, there is one share, so the company is earning 45 crore, in front of that, in front of each
share, in front of one share, the company is earning 45 crore, but if if if you have to share
reliance industry with the market then how much will you get, if you want to share reliance industry with the market
so the company is earning 45 crore per share, 45 crore per one share, but if I want to buy one share
from the market, I will have to pay 2010 rupees to buy that share, so I will go to excel again,
so company is earning 45 crore per share, but if I want to buy that one share,
how many times more will I have to pay 44.67, who say, you rise to earnings ratio
okay, 44.67, this is company per share, company is earning per share 45 rupees,
but you will have to pay 44.61 times more to buy that share from the company, that is called
the PEE ratio, right price earnings ratio, that per share company is earning so much,
that per share is earning so much, that per share is earning so much more times, how many more times
do you have to pay to buy the shares from the market, so PEE is nothing but market price,
market price, divided by EPS earning per share, right point number one before I go ahead,
is this understood everybody, understood have you understood what is PEE, okay super,
now let's look at something called as PB, okay, I have already told you,
this is not necessary, if PEE is higher, then it is expensive,
if it is less, then it is cheap, it is not like that, you have to understand when to pay for it,
when to pay for it, when to pay for it, let's now try and understand what is PB,
Sanjay ji yours is the excel, okay, now let's try and understand what is PB, okay, I will come to the
excel in a bit Sanjay ji, just give me some time, what is PB, PB means market price,
divided by book value, now first of all let's understand what is book value,
market price I am sure everybody knows, what is book value, book value means if today if I
company shut down, today if I want to shut down my company, how much money will the shareholders
receive is called book value, but love pay attention, so let's say today if I want to shut down my
company, what will I have to do, I will have to sell all my assets, right, let's say after selling all my
assets I got 100 rupees, what do I do with this 100 rupees, I will have to pay back
all liabilities, where I have taken money, I will have to pay back everybody, let's say liabilities
was 60 rupees, the remaining amount 40 rupees is what is available for shareholders, available for
shareholders, so if I shut down my company today, I sell all my assets, I have taken money from the
money I gave all the money, then 40 rupees will be saved in the company, 40 rupees is called book value,
40 rupees is called book value, all assets minus all liabilities is book value, now this book value
is 40 rupees, right, this is for every shareholder of the company, this is for every shareholder of the company,
correct, right, and take it in your company, it is 20 shares, it is 20 shares in your company,
so how much will each shareholder receive, so you will say 40 divided by 20 shares,
each shareholder will get 2 rupees, each shareholder will get 2 rupees,
if this 40 rupees is available to the entire company, this is 40 rupees for the entire company,
correct, not every shareholder will receive 40, how much while every shareholder receives,
so I am saying 40 divided by the number of shares that are there in the market,
the number of shares that are there in the market are 20, every shareholder receives 2 rupees,
so here the book value per share is 2 rupees, now back, you need to calculate no need to do this,
look here all calculated, the book value of the reliance industry is 720 crores,
if all the assets will be given, all the assets and all the liabilities will be paid off,
so how much will the total of the company be saved, 720 crores,
now if you divide the number of shareholders that are there in the market,
then you will not get 2.7, what does that mean,
if the company is shut down tomorrow, if the company is shut down tomorrow,
then how much will the shareholder get, this is called book value,
so you will hear it, book value per share is 2 rupees,
the company has 40 rupees, the company in total had 40 rupees,
after selling all the assets and paying back all the liabilities, the company had 40 rupees,
if the company has to distribute this back to shareholders, how much will each shareholder receive,
we said 2 rupees, so we said book value per share is 2 rupees,
price to book means market value, what is the market value reliance of 2010,
if the company is shut down tomorrow, then how much will the shareholder receive,
so we are saying, we are saying 2 0 1 0 divided by 720,
so we are saying 2 0 1 0 divided by 720,
if the company is shut down, every share that you hold you will receive 2.79 rupees,
again look you do not have to calculate, it is already calculated and given,
you only have to understand, what is the price to book,
price to book means if the company is shut down tomorrow,
price to book means if the company is shut down tomorrow, per share,
how much money I want to receive, you can click here
and see what it means, but the technicality is not going to go,
just remember, if the company is shut down tomorrow,
so per share you will receive so much money, you are saying, you are saying,
Alpesh, you are correct my bad, I got confused, 720, 720 is what you will get per share,
so let me relate this example to what I was trying to explain to you,
sorry I got lost because I was talking about 2, 3 examples together,
so we said company has 40 rupees, company has 40 rupees,
sorry company has 100 rupees asset, company has 60 rupees of liability,
if company pays off everything, company will have 40 rupees remaining,
we said 40 rupees is for the entire company, 40 rupees is for the entire company,
how much will I receive per share, so we said 2 rupees,
that 2 rupees is this 720, my bad, I got confused in too much of numbers,
so this 2 rupees that I am telling you, this 2 rupees that I am telling you,
that is available per share, is this 720 in Reliance's case,
so if Reliance shuts down tomorrow, for every share you hold,
you will receive 720, but if for every share that you hold, you are going to receive 720,
how many times more are you paying to buy this, so you are paying 2.79 times more,
then the book value to buy the share, so if the company shuts down,
per share you will get 720, but if you want to buy this stock from the market,
per share how much have you to pay, 2010 which is 2.79 times,
so remember it like this, price to earnings and price to book,
earning per share 45 rupees, okay, market price of the share,
market price of the share, let's say 2000 rupees, which means per share, the companies are
earning 45, but how much will you have to pay per share to buy it 2000, which means you are paying 46
times, 46 times the earnings, 46 times earnings to buy the company which is called the PE ratio,
similarly the book value per share of Reliance is 720, which means if the company has to shut down
today, how much will you receive, how much will you receive if the company shuts down 720,
but how much are you paying to buy this stock from the market 2000, which means you are paying 2.7
times the book value to buy this company from the market, this is called price to book,
okay, sorry for the confusion, too many numbers I got lost, but tell me, tell me have you all understood
PEPB now, yes no, consolidated, somebody asked, so I am saying consolidated, okay,
yeah, market price 2000, sorry guys too many numbers, that's okay, I am sure you are understanding
what I am trying to say, okay, so now that you understood PE and PB, okay, yes,
Karthik, I am just coming to that, just give me one moment, now that you understood what is PE and PB,
let me try and help you understand, how do you use this in mutual funds, okay, so very importantly
I am going to take you to a slide, extremely important, look, there are two styles, two style
investing, growth and value, okay, what is growth investing, look, I will show you growth investing,
come what love, a data point quote, look at this, this is the last 40, 50 years of the way US
markets have been used, if you look at up to 2000, up to 2000, remember in 2000 there was a market
crash that happened, but up to 2000 the market was at peak, so let's say from 1989 to 2000,
the market was going up, going up in 2000 PE, correct, so not pay attention, then from 1989 to 2000,
when markets go up, the market is going up, then you see growth stocks are performing,
growth stock, view on it, growth gave 6-20% returns, value gave 2-90, so remember whenever the markets
are going up, from bottom to peak, growth stocks perform, okay, now look at the other example,
2000 when crash came, market, after that what will happen, 2000, 2000 and 6, so 2000 was peak,
2000 was peak, say 2006, right, so from the peak, when the market started falling, which stocks
perform, look 15% value stocks, value stocks perform, and this keeps repeating, decade,
back up, 2007, 2008, 2007, 2008, which crash came, from that day onwards, 2020, market
has been crazy, right, what has performed, growth stocks, now what is the take of it, what am I
trying to tell you, pay attention, while you are near peak, while you are near peak, always invest
in value stocks, why is because when you are close to peak, 2000, you've seen peak
a bad, it's the value stocks which perform, right, and whenever you are away from the peak,
or let's say bottom, or away from peak, away from peak, okay, always invest in growth,
so 1989 to 1929 when the markets were going up, when they were not at the peak,
growth stocks gave the most return, when the markets were at the peak, value stocks gave the
most return, from the bottom, or 2007, 2008, 2020, growth stocks gave the most returns,
always remember, and keep this in your mind, when you are near peak, always invest in value stocks
or value funds, when the markets are at bottom, or away from peak, when the markets are at bottom,
or away from peak, always invest in growth stocks, or growth funds, now the most important question,
so how do you do that, simple, now what do you do, let's look at the same funds,
ICICI, you chip, nipon, large cap, okay, now let's try and understand,
mind, mind, mind, mind that these two funds are qualified, assume both of these funds qualified,
in R5 step process, now how do I decide whether ICICI have luchip or nipon large cap,
which among these will play a value strategy for me, and which will play a growth strategy for me
how do you do that, simple, go to value research not for me okay, now search for let's say
I see I see I you chip okay go down do you see this they give you a portfolio PV and a portfolio PE
so let me write that down first here that's I see I see I you chip portfolio PE is
24.50 and portfolio PV is
2.33 okay now let's look at nip on large gap okay let's keep going down check this here again
portfolio PV 1.79 portfolio PE 18.49 now understand this very well like I told you
is not necessary higher PE is bad and is not necessary lower PE is good right where you have PE and PV
is more than this is growth where you have PE and PV is less than this is value okay which means
if if you think today you are a peak today like I think the market probably peak is very low
today right now how will I know that for that you have to do a little reading you will have to
look at the situation you will have to figure out how markets are behaving you will have to your
fund manager commentary and do various other things right but the point is let's say I think
market peak is very low okay and from here maybe 8-10 percent can go up from that it can go up from that
it may not go up from that and I have to choose between I see I see a blue chip and nip on large gap
I will put my money in nip on large gap why you can nip on large gap portfolio PV is lower than
I see I see a blue chip and hence if I do talk about these two fronts then this will give me
more value and this will give me growth and if I am peak today then I want to invest in value
so I will put my nip on large gap but if I look at the bottom of the bottom let's say let's go back to
April April when the market was and we were in the bottom of the bottom of the bottom of the bottom of the bottom
if I decide which fund I want to invest I want to invest in growth
right so then I would have chosen I see I see a blue chip to invest in
have I been able to communicate have you understood yes or no friends I will not be able to answer any
fund related questions so please don't ask me fund related questions I have to general definitely
many things I can tell you and also teaching you where will you get the data from one small suggestion
you go and see how did I get the fund ppb bhavesh you have to go to zoom sorry you have to go to
value research value research is the name of the fund you go down like you will go down
you will get a concentration and valuation portfolio p portfolio pp will get
okay now now just to answer one of your questions just to answer one of your questions
have you all seen that over the last three years four years value stocks or value funds have not
done well this is exactly the reason because the market was moving up and when the markets are moving up
right you will always have the growth funds with higher p and higher pb outperforming funds
with lower p lower pb which you call as value of course it's a tricky task tricky is difficult
to figure out that you are not a peak or a peak but my thought process is very simple whenever you are
comfortable taking equity risk okay growth may pass out whenever you think equity risk is not
difficult at this time value may pass out that's the best way you can look at it okay just give me one
go ahead if you all if you all have understood it so far you become you will have to keep monitoring
the markets okay guys now what I'm going to teach you is slightly technical
Ashwini can I can I just go ahead and take another 15 20 minutes or rather let me ask let me ask the
participants I think it's already yeah I am I think 10 minutes should not be an issue I'm pretty sure
everyone is actually in sync let me let me just check with the participants guys sure this is something
that you can do very easy but I'm going to teach you and even more technical method even more technical
method but I will take 20 minutes will you stay on the call okay perfect perfect so I am hoping not to
see participants dropping out of the call for 20 minutes right pay attention now I'm going to teach you
something very interesting okay so it's a myth it's a myth that PE helps you understand whether
the market is over valued or under under the PE the market say to a greater extent
Zyada Lena Deena is not now I'll tell you why I'm telling you what I'm telling you so pay attention
to something very interesting market may punch valuation ratios that market may punch valuation ratios
sir PE is not a happy a happy a happy baby a happy baby by a bit of a happy price to sales
or a happy dividend deal now I'm going to explain to you each of these remaining ratios before I
show you the data points right up what is extremely important for you to understand is right
if those stock K beach may have comparison career like say for example
may let's say let's go to HDFC bank now I'm saying HDFC bank PE let's say 23.27
23.27 HDFC bank now let's see Kootak bank okay Kootak has a PE of 48.43 okay now you will say
looking at the PE that Kootak mind rise expensive and HDFC bank is cheap but just for your understanding
by you are trying to look at banks banks to judge for the PE ratio is not used
price to equity ratio is not applicable to judge judge banks right what I want you to do what I want
you to understand is you understand that the market has five valuation ratios and for every
thing is that price equity ratio is not seen so price equity ratio is seen for which
is the IP companies pharma companies and FMCG companies only for them you can see the ratio if
you want to see that TCS and Infosys what is in it then you will see the ratio you want to see the
HUL and ITC what is in it you will see the PE ratio you want to see the Furnmmer and Furnmmer in Furnmmer
what is in it you will see the PE ratio if you want to see banks right you want to see NBC's right you
want to see real estate companies you want to see Infra companies you want to see their price to
book ratio right so there is no such company that has such assets such assets that do not
appreciate the other sectors you measure the price to book value but banks have gold cash that does not
appreciate it very easily NBC's again they don't have cash they don't have real estate companies
they don't have real estate they don't have real estate companies they don't have land and they don't
appreciate so such companies that have a lot of assets that don't appreciate that they value the price to book
if you want to see that in the banks of the bank what is the best for the price to book ratio okay now
now before you understand EV by if it is so it is a fun song
so that's your missed and so that's your 然後 so they are you know what the cheapest value for you
so let's say I also have a company today I don't have a company today that's where they will find so many
that is determined by market capitalization example. So let's say let's say let's go to
reliance industries. Let's say reliance industries. If I want to buy all the reliance industries
I have to do. What will I have to do? How many shares of the reliance industry are there?
In 2010, right? One share is for 2010 rupees. One share is for 2010 rupees. And how many
such shares are there in the market? Six hundred and seventy six crore. So if I want to buy the entire
reliance industries, I will have to buy all shares and each share is for 2010 rupees. So I
can calculate how much the entire company will study. Let's try and calculate it. So I can
calculate the entire company. One share is for 2010. And how many shares are there? Six,
seventy six crore. One, four, five, six, seven. So how many of the entire company will study me?
How many shares are there in the market? Multiply by 2010 rupees. Okay, number is so big that
I can't see. Right? So I will be able to buy the entire company for some one thirty five
lakh crore. Right? One thirty five lakh crore. Right? Again, you don't have to calculate this.
Look, it is calculated. Market cap. Already calculated. If you want to buy the entire company,
you will have to pay one lakh thirty five thousand crore. Okay? Now, what's the challenge?
Let's say I bought the entire company for one point three five lakh crore. Now, after having bought
the entire company for one point three five lakh crore, I suddenly see a jackpot. Jackpot. What?
Care company money. Okay, sorry, 13.45 lakh crore. Bye, bye. Sorry, guys, you all will have to
pardon me on numbers, please. There are too many numbers floating and it's becoming difficult for
me to keep on watching. But yeah, thank you so much for highlighting. Okay? So let's say 13.13.5 lakh crore.
I will have to spend to buy the entire reliance industries. Now, I have reliance industries.
After buying it, I suddenly see a jackpot. Yeah, reliance industries. Now, the company belongs to me.
But I saw that the bank account has some cash balance. Look, cash. 18.443.
So, I have bought the company, so this cash will also be mine. So, if I spend 13.5 lakh crore
to buy the company, I got this cash which is 8443, which means, how much do I have? 13.5 lakh crore
minus 844 crore because now that I bought this company, the bank account has so much money,
that's all mine. Right? But suddenly, I realized, suddenly, I realized that both the company
has the debt of 2.62,000 crore. Because I have bought a company, I have to pay 2.62 lakh crore.
So, now pay attention. I might have paid cash of 13.5 lakh crore to buy the company.
But I got 8444 cash for free. So, actually, when I bought it, I got 13.5 minus 8.4,
8443 crore. But now, the debt will also be paid by me. So, I will have to pay another 2.62 lakh crore.
Correct? So, in actual sense, how much do I have to pay to buy the company? So, look,
this is the calculation. I paid 13.5 lakh crore, 13 lakh, 50,000. Sorry, I am not getting the number,
the number is too huge. But let's say, I paid 13.5 lakh crore to buy the company.
Now, I will calculate 13 lakh, 50,000, 14 crore, 14,000. Now, this is the number.
So, I paid 13.5 lakh crore to buy the company. But after having bought the company,
I got a jackpot where 8443 crore I received. But then I understood that I have to pay another 2.62 lakh crore,
2.62 lakh crore, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7. So, how much did I actually get the company for?
So, how much did I actually get the company for? So, I am saying, I paid this,
minus I received this, plus I will have to pay the loan also. I got the company for somewhere around
13.76 lakh crore. Okay, 13.76 lakh crore. That 13.76 lakh crore is called the enterprise value
of reliance industries. I am making some mistake in some calculation here, which is why this answer is
not matching. But this answer otherwise will clearly match. I don't know, A cut 0 may,
or A cut 0 may mistake over here. Don't mind, don't mind. But the point that I am trying to tell you
is, but the point that I am trying to tell you is that market capitalization is the amount of money
that I pay. Plus, that is additional that I will have to pay. Minus cash is called the enterprise value.
Or rather in another way, enterprise value is the actual amount of money for which I bought the
company. Market capitalization may be the amount of money that I paid, but enterprise value is the
actual amount for which I actually got the company for. EV, as everybody understood, EV,
in me, yes or no? EV is the actual cost at which I bought the company. Okay, now be attention. Be
attention. Right? Markets, market, there are multiple companies who have a lot of debt.
In the market, there are multiple companies who have a lot of debt. And for us to account for that debt
and for us to account for that debt, right? Enterprise value is the best way to account.
So all the companies in the market, all the companies in the market who have large debt,
right? They are neither valued by price to equity because they are neither valued by price to
book because they are only talking about assets. So companies which have large debt in the market
are compared with each other on EV by EBITDA ratio. So company actually,
how much money divided by company's gross profit or means before interest tax depreciation
and monetization is nothing but operating profit. So company actually, how much money divided by
the operating profit? In simple terms, sorry, this is a two-hour lecture, all else I would have
spent half an hour in explaining what is EV by EBITDA, but in simple sense, companies or sectors
which have large debt are valued at EV by EBITDA. So oil and gas, telecom, power, engineering,
all of these companies are valued on EV by EBITDA, which means if you have two power companies
in between analysis, let's say anti-PC and torrent power, right? You don't look at their
P, you don't look at their PV, you look at their EV by EBITDA. Whose EV by EBITDA is more
and whose EV by EBITDA is less, is what you look at and that is what, that is what you will understand.
Okay, good question, Praveen, why not net profit because net profit may the interest paid on the debt
will get minused. So again, it will not show the actual impact, it will not show the actual
impact of debt, which is why you don't take net profit, Praveen and you take operating profit.
I hope that's clear. Himanshu in Infra-YPB is better is because they have extremely large assets,
right? Because they have a lot of assets which are not depreciating in nature,
price to book makes more sense. Okay, similarly, price to sales, what is that? Simple.
Now, there are industries, there are industries, I'm going to take 10 more minutes, I'm done.
Price to sales means that there are a lot of industries where they have to do continuous
capex. Continuously, they have to keep money in their business, right? For a new product offering in
the market, right? As a company, where continuously money is deployed, right? No, no, projects,
they have to measure the price to sales ratio. One of the classic examples is automobile. What do I
mean? Every time a new variant of vehicle is introduced, right? Every time that new variant is introduced,
capex, new assembly line, new parts, etc. So, you can't judge evy by evy by any time,
because profit margins will be less, because you have capex. That's why, whenever a new product launches,
capex, capital expenditure, those sectors who are priced to books, say, value them.
And last dividend deal, how much dividend do you give versus the stock price, right?
PSU companies judge the dividend deal. So, if you want to compare to PSU companies,
always compare it on the basis of dividend deal. So, now attention, pay attention.
Market may PEPB is not a question. IT for my FMCG company, look at PEP, banks and BFCs
are real estate in fraud, look at PEPB, evy by oil and gas telecom, power, look at evy by beta,
automobiles, look at price to sales, PSU's look at dividend deal. Of course, now the most valid question,
now the most valid question here is, right, is so, Karthik again, because they will take debt,
because they will take debt here, okay. As soon as they take that, evy by evy beta becomes a more
rational ratio to look at. Gurmiji, why dividend deal is because PSU's generally give out a lot of
dividends because the government is the owner, and because dividend plays a major role,
you look at dividend deal. Gotham, so you look at both in ONGC, you look at dividend deals also
and you look at evy by evy beta, but in very simple terms, you look at evy by evy beta, don't look at
dividend deals, okay. Now pay attention to what I am trying to say. How do you, how do you use
this in mutual funds? Now what have I done? Five more minutes. Now this is, this is an actual fund,
I don't want to name the fund, this is an actual fund. What did we do in the last data point that we
spoke of? Amne, pura fund ka pb or pura fund ka p e leia, correct? Now I am saying, pura fund ka pb
or pura fund ka p e leia, may not be the right method. So what do I do here is I now look at each of
these, each of these funds or each of these stocks depending on their relevant ratio. Now look what I
have done. Avenue Supermart, correct? Because FMCG is in that p e ratio, Kotag Mahindra Bank,
because bank is in that p e leia, HDFC, bank cap p e leia, ICICI, bank cap p e leia, okay.
Similarly look, Bharti atel, telecom company is evy by evy beta, reliance industries, evy by beta,
ultra-tech cement, evy by evy beta, Maruti Suzuki, price to sales. Now what I did was,
yeah, per koi b, koi b, PSUNI is like dividend yielding. Now what I did was, instead of looking at
the entire portfolio, instead of looking at the entire portfolio in portfolio, price to equity and
price to book, I have broken down the entire portfolio into relevant ratios, price to book,
price to equity, wherever it is applicable, price to book, wherever that is applicable,
evy by evy beta, wherever that is applicable, price to sales, wherever that is applicable and dividend
yield, wherever that is applicable, right? Now what I have done, what I have done, simple,
this website, this website, and in front of that company, whatever relevant data is written,
like for example, I went to avenue supermod, sorry, I went to avenue supermod, okay.
Now in front of that calculated, p e is given, do you see p e, avenue supermod of 154, so I have
154 link here, this data is slightly old, so the data will not completely match, right? Similarly,
let's say I went to put up my hinderabank, put up my hinderabank, here p b already calculated
5.17, so many, here per 5.17 link here, now what is important, what did I do, what did I do?
I found out the average p e of the portfolio, what is average p of the portfolio pay attention,
in avenue supermark, 7.141% is like this, into that p e, plus now I do not want to buy the quota,
now I want to buy the info system, so I will say 5.47 into 16.84, plus 5.27 into 75, plus
so wherever p e, I will multiply it, 4.59 into 72.4%, plus 4.06 into 57.22, plus 3.22 into 19.07 plus
2.18 into 50.17 plus 1.57 into 45 plus 1.33 into 58.57 plus, so I kept multiplying wherever
p e was involved, now when I did this is where I got the average p e of the portfolio,
look I got the average p of the portfolio, 21.05, this is very different from the average p that value
research was showing, value research has multiplied by the entire p e, but now I am saying,
most quota, hinderabank, hdfc, ic, ic, kp, multiply it, because it is not necessary,
because it is the relevant ratio, similarly I found out the average p b of the portfolio,
7.41 into this, plus 6.06 into this, plus, so wherever p b is relevant, you only
multiply that, plus similarly I kept doing that, now pay attention, that is how I got,
that is how I got the weighted average p b, p e e by a bit times sales of this particular portfolio,
now what do you have to do, simple, let's say this is fund a, and let's say this is fund b,
okay, jiska data here, now tell me, fund a fund b, you are at the peak of the market
or close to peak, will you invest in fund a or fund b, a tarun you get this portfolio from
monthly portfolio disclosure, monthly portfolio disclosure of the fund,
you will forward your RM portfolio, monthly portfolio disclosure, you are near the peak,
you invest in fund a or fund b, absolutely guys, look, in fund a, average p, come a, fund b, say,
fund a, average p b, come a, fund a, maybe by a bit, come a, average p b, come a, because you are
peak, this is value, this is growth, so there are two ways, do not work, if you do not want to do a lot of
manner, go to value research, look at the portfolio, p b, p, and decide what is value, what is growth,
but if you really want to deep dive in the portfolio, find out the weight of your average p, p e,
p b, buy a bit of price to sales and dividend yield of the portfolio, then determine whether it is
value or growth, and then choose between fund a and fund, so very quickly, last five minutes,
before I, before I let you go, right, what do you do, step one, look at the past performance,
and then determine which funds do you really want to even look at investing in,
bowling returns, bowling returns, then look at sotino, then look at alpha, then look at
a capture, down capture, once this is through, easier way, easier way is to determine looking at the
price to book and price to equity using value research, if this number is high, this is growth,
use this at the bottom, if price to book and price to equity is low, this is value, use this at the peak,
see if you want to deep dive in the portfolio, convert the entire portfolio into price to book,
price to equity, e, v, buy a bit of price to sales and dividend yield, okay, wherever you get this
as high, you know it is growth, and whenever you get this as low, you know it is value,
this will get invested at bottom and this will get invested at peak, right,
if you thought you could randomly invest in any fund that comes your way, which is why you keep
getting random returns, right, the simplest relationship of this versus what I'm trying to teach you was,
you saw it in the past 3 years, 5 years, only growth funds have returned the value,
it is not a value, had you not done, forget about see, had you done simple B, also you would have
understood which fund to put money in, which one would have performed and which would have not
performed and you would have not chosen money, this is how you ideally end up selecting, looking at
the past and the futuristic data, right, or how do you select the right equity funds, before I take
your questions or let you go, one very simple thing, there are some of you all here on the call who are
there on my broadcast list, I run a small broadcast list where I try educating you on a regular basis
by writing articles or writing some simple data points, making market new simpler for you to understand,
so that you understand, market may joby changes over it, equity, debt funds, what change will
if you want to get added to my broadcast list, here is my name and my number, you will have to save my name
in your phone directory or else you will not receive my broadcast, save your name in my phone directory,
send me a whatsapp with your name, just write your name, I will add you to my broadcast,
by that I will continuously be in a position to educate you over a period of time outside of this
particular session of two hours, save my name, send me a whatsapp with your name, just write your name,
I will add you to my broadcast, by that I hope I have been able to add some value to your existing
knowledge around equity funds guys, thank you for showing patience and staying by for two and a half
hours, I am glad that there were 350 people who stood by for two and a half hours, if at all you all have
any questions you will think I can add some value, you have my number, leave me a message and
I will be more than happy to answer all the questions that y'all have, right, on stvg over to you,
if they have questions I will take them up personally on my own, I think we already spent two and a half
hours, they can ask their questions personally to me, so I think I had rightly mentioned that it
actually requires supreme expertise to hold and connect with audience for more than two hours,
thank you, thank you so much Ketan and I am pretty sure everyone has really loved this session
and I mean we at Mindra Manualized Mutual Fund will ensure that we keep on adding such kind of
values to our partners like you and we will again try and get hold Ketan maybe sometime in your future
for all of you because I mean I can actually see and understand there are a lot of unanswered
questions, so everyone would again want to reconnect with you, so I think we all will take a leave and
thank you so much Ketan and thank you everyone for sharing such a such time, thank you so much.
Thank you, thank you, thanks, bye bye everyone.